Mohit Bidikar

+44 7724083477 Mohitbidikar4@gmail.com 27 Monastery Road, Liverpool, L6 0BH

I recently completed my MSc in Advanced Computer Science from the University of York in September 2023. With over 4 years of experience, I specialize in developing Full Stack Web Applications and Cross-Platform Mobile Applications. I am proficient in a range of technologies like JavaScript (React, Node, Express), Java, PostgreSQL, MongoDB and Docker. Click on the following link to view my portfolio. (View Portfolio)

Professional Experience

Frontend Developer (part time while pursuing MSc) Stockholm Environment Institute, York, UK | Apr 2023 – Oct 2023

 Successfully redesigned the React frontend of both the SAMHE public-facing site and the SAMHE web app, which is employed by over 1000 schools in the UK for real-time air quality monitoring.

Senior Software Developer

Samasa Innovations pvt ltd, Goa, India | Dec 2020 – Aug 2022

- Successfully developed the backend for a Hotel and Hospitality management application, serving diverse clients in India and UAE, utilizing Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Collaborated with the frontend team to ensure seamless application functionality.

Trainee Software Engineer

Goa electronics ltd, Goa, India | Nov 2018 - Oct 2020

- Contributed to the development of the Goa Services Web Application, a critical tool for government departments in Goa, India, by engineering robust solutions with Java and PostgreSQL
- Authored automated test scripts for key modules using Selenium Webdriver.
- Integrated Google Maps into mobile and web applications.

Education

Master of Science (Advanced Computer Science) at University of York (Sep 2022 - Sep 2023)

Bachelor of Engineering (Information Technology) at Goa College of Engineering (2013 - 2017)

Skills

Javascript:

Node, Express, React

Java:

Apache wicket

APIs:

GraphQL and REST with Express

Database:

PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MongoDB

Containers/Microservices:

Docker

Cross-platform Apps:

Cordova, React Native

Testing:

TestNG, Selenium WebDriver, Jest

Version control:

Github, Gitlab

Project management:

Jira, Github

Hosting:

AWS (ec2), Netlify, Heroku, Render